Dante is thirty-five years old.
Dante ha trentacinque anni.
He is in the middle of his life.
È nel mezzo della sua vita.
One day, he wakes up in a forest.
Un giorno, si sveglia in un bosco.
The forest is dark.
Il bosco è oscuro.
He is afraid.
Ha paura.
He does not know where he is.
Non sa dove è.
He does not remember how he got here.
Non ricorda come è arrivato qui.
"Where am I?" says Dante.
"Dove sono?" dice Dante.
He looks up and sees a mountain.
Guarda in alto e vede una montagna.
The sun shines on the top.
Il sole brilla sulla cima.
"I must climb that mountain," thinks Dante.
"Devo salire quella montagna," pensa Dante.
He starts to walk toward the mountain.
Comincia a camminare verso la montagna.
But an animal blocks the road.
Ma un animale blocca la strada.
It is a leopard. A big wild cat.
È una lonza. Un grande gatto selvatico.
The leopard is fast and dangerous.
La lonza è veloce e pericolosa.
Dante is afraid but keeps walking.
Dante ha paura ma continua a camminare.
Then he sees a lion.
Poi vede un leone.
The lion is big and strong.
Il leone è grande e forte.
It raises its head and roars.
Alza la testa e ruggisce.
Dante trembles.
Dante trema.
Then a she-wolf arrives.
Poi arriva una lupa.
The she-wolf is thin and hungry.
La lupa è magra e ha fame.
Her eyes are terrible.
I suoi occhi sono terribili.
Dante cannot go forward.
Dante non può andare avanti.
He goes back into the dark forest.
Torna nel bosco oscuro.
"I am lost," says Dante.
"Sono perduto," dice Dante.
But then he sees a man.
Ma poi vede un uomo.
"Who are you?" asks Dante.
"Chi sei?" chiede Dante.
"I am Virgil," says the man.
"Io sono Virgilio," dice l'uomo.
"I am a poet. I died a long time ago."
"Sono un poeta. Sono morto molto tempo fa."
"Why are you here?" asks Dante.
"Perché sei qui?" chiede Dante.
"A woman sent me. Her name is Beatrice."
"Una donna mi ha mandato. Il suo nome è Beatrice."
"Beatrice!" says Dante. "My love!"
"Beatrice!" dice Dante. "Il mio amore!"
"Beatrice watches you from heaven," says Virgil.
"Beatrice ti guarda dal cielo," dice Virgilio.
"She is afraid for you."
"Ha paura per te."
"You must come with me," says Virgil.
"Devi venire con me," dice Virgilio.
"There is another road to the mountain."
"C'è un'altra strada per la montagna."
"But first we must pass through Hell."
"Ma prima dobbiamo passare per l'Inferno."
"Hell?" says Dante. "I am afraid."
"L'Inferno?" dice Dante. "Ho paura."
"Do not be afraid," says Virgil. "I am with you."
"Non avere paura," dice Virgilio. "Io sono con te."
They walk together in the forest.
Camminano insieme nel bosco.
They arrive in front of a great gate.
Arrivano davanti a una grande porta.
On the gate it is written:
Sulla porta c'è scritto:
"Abandon all hope, you who enter."
"Lasciate ogni speranza, voi che entrate."
Dante reads and trembles.
Dante legge e trema.
"Courage," says Virgil.
"Coraggio," dice Virgilio.
Virgil takes Dante's hand.
Virgilio prende la mano di Dante.
They enter through the gate together.
Entrano insieme nella porta.
The journey through Hell begins.
Il viaggio nell'Inferno comincia.